# Nived Subbarayan

## QA Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom | Full Working Rights

in Nived Subbarayan Nived Subbarayan



As a Quality Engineer with over 5 years of experience, Nived is dedicated to advancing his knowledge and skills in the field of Quality Engineering. He aims to broaden his exposure to different markets and products, and to improve his technical abilities to ensure the highest quality standards are met. Nived strives to establish himself as a respected professional and leader in the product development industry, known for his expertise in Quality Engineering. Please note, Nived is based in London, United Kingdom, with full working rights.

Languages Master	<b>Automation</b> <i>Master</i>	Services Master	Databases Intermediate
Python Typescript	Playwright Cypress	AWS Azure Jira	PostgreSQL MySql
Javascript C# Go	Postman DevOps	GitLab Bitbucket	DBT DBT Cloud
	PyTest Docker		Snowflake
Web3 Intermediate			
Hardhat Solidity			
Smart Contracts			

# **WORK EXPERIENCE (3)**

**QA Software Engineer** at Chainlink Labs

Jun 2024 - Jul 2024

### **Q** London, United Kingdom (Remote)

Chainlink Labs is the leading provider of secure and reliable Web3 services that have enabled trillions of dollars in transaction value across DeFi, insurance, gaming, NFTs, and other major industries. Chainlink Web3 services enhance smart contracts by connecting them to real-world data sources and off-chain computation across any blockchain and provide global enterprises with a universal gateway to all blockchains. Chainlink Labs is dedicated to the development and integration of Chainlink as the industry-standard Web3 services platform connecting the world to blockchains.

- Hired as a QA Software Engineer to help ensure reliability of the products being developed, automate tests and assist in building out test tooling in Golang
- Developed a solid understanding of how Chainlink oracles bridge the gap between blockchains and real-world data, including their functionalities and
  use cases within Web3 applications

#### Quality Engineering Architect at Slalom Build

Aug 2021 - May 2024

#### Melbourne, Australia

Slalom is a modern consulting firm focused on strategy, technology, and business transformation. Slalom redefines what's possible and create what's next.

- Lead Quality Engineer involved in architecting and implementing 'shift left' modern quality solutions in multiple projects spanning from web applications, mobile applications, database modernisations and infrastructure modernisations
- Proficient in working in cross functional teams and coaching Software, Data, Platform and other Quality Engineers on best quality practices throughout the whole software development lifecycle
- Demonstrated exceptional leadership and architectural skills which led to a role promotion from Senior Quality Engineer to Quality Engineering Architect

#### Quality Engineering Consultant at Accenture

Mar 2019 - Aug 2021

#### Melbourne, Australia

Accenture is a leading global professional services company that helps the world's leading businesses, governments and other organisations build their digital core, optimise their operations, accelerate revenue growth and enhance citizen services—creating tangible value at speed and scale.

- Working as a systems QA Engineer in client operations and project delivery
- Adept in Agile working methodologies. Received an ICAgile Certified Professional certification
- Proficient in working in teams both domestically and internationally

#### PROJECTS (9)

Government Client | Census Web Application at Slalom Build

Jan 2024 - May 2024

Melbourne, Australia

Selenium Java API Testing Postman React AWS JIRA

Quality Engineer tasked with ensuring the reliability of a critical nationwide census web application used by over 20 million users.

- Lead Quality Engineer for the functional testing team ensuring that features were built to a high standard
- Coached developers to be able to build reliably to handle high peak loads and prevent downtime
- Developed robust test automation frameworks leveraging Selenium, guaranteeing smooth performance of the census form during critical user periods

#### Financial Services Client | Engagement Application at Slalom Build

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

Melbourne, Australia

Specflow C# .NET API Testing Typescript Javascript Postman Playwright Appium React GitLab AWS JIRA

Led the quality modernisation effort for a mobile application and front-end web application using a behaviour-driven framework.

- Led a Quality Engineering team to maintain quality standards and hit all release deadlines
- Built a custom shippable back-end API testing template for use in all the client's back-end repositories
- Coached developers to be able to add their own tests and create a cohesive quality-driven team
- Demoed new features to the wider client team in their company wide showcase calls

#### Retail Client | Merchant Web Application at Slalom Build

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

Melbourne, Australia



Led the quality modernisation effort for a front-end web application by utilising Playwright to overhaul the current test automation framework.

- Established and implemented best practices for the development and pipeline processes to ensure that the highest standards of quality were met throughout this and future projects
- Utilised AWS Cloudwatch to set up monitoring and alerting for performance triggers

#### Retail Client | Notification Service at Slalom Build

Mar 2022 - Jun 2022

Melbourne, Australia



Directed the quality strategy and implementation for a notification service modernisation project, overseeing the overhaul of the way emails and text messages are sent at large scale business entities.

- Developed custom python scripts to programatically access a test gmail and twilio inboxes to validate the successful sending of email and text messages
- Integrated the custom tests with the CI/CD pipelines to optimise test automation in the software development lifecycle

#### Retail Client | Data Platform at Slalom Build

Jan 2022 - Mar 2022

Melbourne, Australia



Coordinated the architecture, design, and implementation of a data quality strategy for a modernised analytics platform and services on AWS Cloud in a cross-functional team. This enabled the agency to offer reliable analytics as a shared service to customers through the use of native and 3rd party components.

- Solidified my understanding of best quality practices in data-driven projects
- Implemented modern data quality checks in the CI/CD pipelines

#### Oil & Gas Client | Site Owner Web Application at Slalom Build

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Cypress Typescript Javascript Azure AWS JIRA

Led the development and implementation of a quality strategy for a consolidated front-end web application for physical site owners, managing testing, defect identification, and cross-functional collaboration for successful delivery.

#### myWizardAiOps | Automated Ticketing Platform at Accenture

Aug 2019 - Aug 2021

Melbourne, Australia

Cypress Typescript Javascript AWS JIRA

Led a Quality Engineering team tasked with the creation and implementation of best Quality Engineering practices for an internal Automated Ticket resolution SaaS product which Accenture sells to clients.

#### Government Client | Systems Tester at Accenture

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019

Melbourne, Australia

Manual Testing Test Plans Documentation Test Cases Agile JIRA

Systems tester involved in managing release processes and working in an agile evironment. Tasked with manual testing and creating test plans and test documention to ensure government standards and release deadlines are met.

Summit Participant at Engineers Without Borders Australia

Jun 2018 - Jul 2018

**♀** Kuching, Malaysia

Volunteering Thesis Human-Centred Design

Undertook a humanitarian engineering trip to Borneo to further my human-centred design skills and cultural awareness.

Conducted as part of my honours thesis titled "Optimisation of off-grid solar photovoltaic systems in developing areas"

#### EDUCATION (2)

Bachelor of Engineering (Honours) Mechatronic Systems at The Australian National University

2015 - 2018

**GPA:** 6.3/7.0

Study Abroad Engineering Exchange Program at The University of Wisconsin-Madison

2017 - 2017

#### AWARDS —

Certified Solutions Architect - Associate at AWS

Certified Cloud Practitioner at AWS

**Certified Professional Certification** at ICAgile

2 x Slalom Build Team Mogul at Slalom Build

Awarded to members of the best performing Slalom Build team over the guarter

New Colombo Plan Scholarship at The Australian National University

Due to my high academic standing, I have received a New Colombo Plan Scholarship valued at \$3,000 from the Australian National University

## **Honours Thesis** at The Australian National University

Completed an honours thesis titled "Optimisation of off-grid solar photovoltaic systems in developing areas"

## LANGUAGES —

# **English**

Native Speaker